Guide to the R. Stuart Hummel Family Papers M1607
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series IX. PHOTOGRAPHS, Circa 1870-2005
  - William M. Hummel, photograph album: includes photos of the aftermath of the 1968 Washington D.C. riots that followed the assassination of Martin Luther King, Jr.: also photos of travels in Europe., circa 1965-1968 (Box 122, Volume 1)
  - William M. Hummel, photograph album: photos of travels in France, mainly Paris; also includes postcards., circa 1966 (Box 122, Volume 2)
  - William M. Hummel, photograph album, circa 1966-1970 (Box 122, Volume 3)
  - William M. Hummel, photograph album, circa 1969 (Box 122, Volume 4)
  - Hummel family and miscellaneous portraits (mostly duplicates) (Box 240, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (mostly copy prints and duplicates) (Box 241)
- Series X. ARTWORK
  This small series contains one fragment of Ming Dynasty paper currency, a set of Chinese Door God prints, missionary posters, and miscellaneous artwork.
  The fragment of Ming Dynasty currency, Door God prints, and missionary posters are available online.
  - Ming Dynasty paper currency, fragment of note, probably from the Hongwu period, circa 1385-1487 (Flat-box 278, Folder 1)
  - Chinese door god prints; ancient guardian Yu Lu; ancient guardian Shen Shu, circa 1900 (Flat-box 279, Folder 1)
  - Chinese door god prints; three star gods (Fu, Lu, and Shao who grant blessings, rank and wealth, and longevity); five sons fighting for the helmet ( fighting to come first in the final examination of the Civil Service Examination), circa 1900 (Flat-box 279, Folder 2)
  - Chinese door god prints; the dark faced warrior Yuchi Gong; the white faced warrior Qin Qiong. (These two Tang dynasty generals were famed in popular tradition for having frightened away demons that were troubling the Tang emperor Taizong., circa 1900 (Flat-box 279, Folder 3)
  - Chinese door god prints; wealth-bringing boys, circa 1900 (Flat-box 279, Folder 4)
  - Chinese door god prints; officials bringing a rise in rank and a rise in official salary, circa 1900 (Flat-box 279, Folder 5)
  - Chinese kitchen god print; kitchen god and his wife, 1932 (Flat-box 279, Folder 6)
  - Missionary posters, probably used for instruction, circa 1900 (Flat-box 280, Folder 1)
  - Silk ribbon, circa 1900 (Flat-box 280, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous artwork (Flat-box 280, Folder 3)
- Series XI. AUDIOVISUAL
  This series contains various audiovisual formats found throughout the collection; includes early recordisc interviews, one film reel, many audiocassettes, CDs and DVD with recorded interview of R. Stuart Hummel and others.
  - Stuart and Hummel families, mission scenes, etc. (3 reels, Ciné-Kodak Kodachrome film), circa 1942 (Box 233)
  - R. Stuart Hummel to Kathleen Hummel (2 Packard-Bell Phonocords), 1942 March (Box 233, Folder 1)
  - Radio music (Recordisc), 1942 June 13 (Box 233, Folder 2)
  - Rachel Anna Golden Stuart and Mildred Stuart Hummel (Wilcox-Gay Recordio Disc and audiocassette), 1942 June 14 (Box 233, Folder 3)
  - R. Stuart Hummel, William F. Hummel Jr., etc. (2 Recordiscs), 1942 June 14 (Box 233, Folder 4)
  - George Golden Stuart, Mildred and William Hummel, etc. (Wilcox-Gay Recordio Disc), 1942 June 15 (Box 233, Folder 5)
  - Isabelle and Max (?) (Music City Record), circa 1942 (Box 233, Folder 6)
  - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., interviews, discussion of China years, Shansi maps and documents, Library of Congress, etc. (3 audiocassettes, 8 audiotapes, and typed transcription), 1968-1974 (Box 234)
  - R. Stuart Hummel and Sharman Hummel, conversation regarding William F. Hummel and Arthur W. Hummel letters, Harriet Low diaries, Edwin G. Beale, etc. (audiocassette), 1982 (Box 234)
  - R. Stuart Hummel, conversations with parents, William F. Hummel and Mildred Stuart Hummel (3 audiotapes and 11 audiocassettes in binder), 1970 (Box 235)
  - Conversations with June and John Thomson, Fred Hummel, and other family members (27 audiocassettes in three binders), 1993-1998 (Box 236)
  - Golden family, Abram Lee Golden (4 audiocassettes), 1979-1980 (Box 237)
  - Strecker family, George E. Strecker (audiocassette), 1981 (Box 237)
  - Wehking family, Johanna Gray, phone conversations (5 audiocassettes), 1980-1982 (Box 237)
  - Wehking family, conversation with Margaret Perisho (audiocassette), 1983 (Box 237)
  - Hummel family reunion (2 VHS tapes and miscellaneous papers), 1990 (Box 237)
  - Hummel family, Geraldine Murphy (audiocassette), 1998 (Box 237)
  - Kenneth Maurer and R. Stuart Hummel, conversation, (audiocassette), 1999 (Box 237)
  - R. Stuart Hummel, video interview by Andy Lang (2 DVDs), 2004 (Box 237)
  - Dr. Corbett, (DVD, removed from R. Stuart Hummel and John Rees and Clarissa Dong file), 2006 (Box 237)
  - Dolly and party (DVD, removed from R. Stuart Hummel and John Rees and Clarissa Dong file), 2007 (Box 237)
  - R. Stuart Hummel and Ada Luella Krughoff Huelsman, conversation (13 audiocassettes), 1980-1982 (Box 249)
- Series XII. PUBLICATIONS, 1887-1997
  This series contains periodicals, reports, and pamphlets collected by the Stuart and Hummel families while living in China, mostly published by the Central China Mission and related organizations.
  Publications through circa 1940 are available online.
  - Central China Mission, annual report, 1887 (Box 226, Folder 1)
  - Central China Mission, annual report, 1888 (Box 226, Folder 2)
  - Central China Mission, annual report, 1891 (Box 226, Folder 3)
  - Central China Mission, annual report, 1892 (Box 226, Folder 4)
  - Central China Mission, annual report, 1893 (Box 226, Folder 5)
  - Central China Mission, annual report, 1895 (Box 226, Folder 6)
  - Central China Mission, annual report, 1896 (Box 226, Folder 7)
  - Central China Mission, annual report, 1897 (Box 226, Folder 8)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1926 (Box 226, Folder 9)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1927 (Box 226, Folder 10)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1928 (Box 226, Folder 11)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1929 (Box 226, Folder 12)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1930 (Box 226, Folder 13)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1931 (Box 226, Folder 14)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1932 (Box 226, Folder 15)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1933 (Box 226, Folder 16)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1934 (Box 226, Folder 17)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1935 (Box 226, Folder 18)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, 1938 (Box 227, Folder 1)
  - Central China Conference, minutes, miscellaneous (Box 227, Folder 2)
  - Central China Conference Bulletin, 1934-1935 (Box 227, Folder 3)
  - Central China Conference, duplicates (Box 227, Folder 4)
  - Central China Record, 1904 (Box 227, Folder 5)
  - Triennial Report of Wuhu General Hospital, 1891-1894 (Box 227, Folder 6)
  - Animus, 1898-1900 (Box 227, Folder 7)
  - The China Mission of the Methodist Episcopal Church, circa 1900 (Box 227, Folder 8)
  - Bible Study (Soochow University), 1905 (Box 227, Folder 9)
  - University of Nanking Magazine, 1911-1913 (Box 227, Folder 10)
  - Nanking Union Church Bulletin, 1917-1921 (Box 227, Folder 11)
  - Nanking Union Church Bulletin, 1921-1932 (Box 227, Folder 12)
  - Nanking Union Church Bulletin, miscellaneous (Box 227, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous bulletins, circa 1919-1930 (Box 227, Folder 14)
  - The Educational Review (Educational Association of China), vol. II, no. 6, June 1919 (Box 227, Folder 15)
  - Let Us Think (Women’s Foreign Missionary Society), circa 1920 (Box 227, Folder 16)
  - Nanking Foreign School Catalogue, 1923-1924 (Box 227, Folder 17)
  - Women and Missions, vol. IV, no. 5, August 1927 (Box 227, Folder 18)
  - Agriculture and Forestry Notes (University of Nanking), no. 27, June 1932 (Box 227, Folder 19)
  - Arthur John Bowen, Missionary-Educator, circa 1940 (Box 227, Folder 20)
  - Centenary Missionary Conference, 1907 (Flat-box 228)
  - The China Connection, 1988-1991 (Box 229, Folder 1)
  - The China Connection, 1992-1994 (Box 229, Folder 2)
  - The China Connection, 1995-1997 (Box 229, Folder 3)
  - The China Connection, 1997-1999 (Box 229, Folder 4)
  - The China Connection, 1999-2002 (Box 229, Folder 5)
  - The China Connection Directory, 1989 (Box 229, Folder 6)
- Series XIII. MURIEL BOONE
  This series contains a set of typescripts for Muriel Boone's unpublished book Four Flags over a Changing China, documenting the history of China through the revolutionary events that occurred between 1880-1949, particularly her own experiences of these events; in addition to multiple drafts of the printed typescript, there are also digital copies of the typescript and photographs for the book on CD; the series also includes related correspondence and biographical materials.
  - Muriel Boone, correspondence, circa 1983-1990 (Box 230, Folder 1)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 230, Folder 2)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 230, Folder 3)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 230, Folder 4)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 230, Folder 5)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 230, Folder 6)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 231, Folder 1)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 231, Folder 2)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 231, Folder 3)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 231, Folder 4)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, typescripts, circa 1983-2005 (Box 231, Folder 5)
  - Muriel Boone, Four Flags over a Changing China, text and photographs (5 compact discs), 2005-2006 (Box 237)
  - Muriel Boone, biographical materials (Box 232, Folder 1)
  - Muriel Boone, biographical materials (Box 232, Folder 2)
  - Frances Boone, William Henry Boone, typescript, 1993 (Box 232, Folder 3)
  - Frances Boone, William Henry Boone, typescript, 1993 (Box 232, Folder 4)
  - Boone family scrapbook (Box 232, Folder 5)
  - Boone family, miscellaneous materials (Box 232, Folder 6)
- Series XIV. CHINA SUBJECT FILES
  This series contains articles and subject files on China, including notes and personal narratives about life in China by R. Stuart Hummel, his sister June Hummel Thomson, and others.
  Files with original, unpublished material of high research value are available online.
  - Boxer Rebellion, 1900 (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - R. Stuart Hummel, China memories (Box 180, Folder 2)
  - June Hummel Thomson, China memories (Box 180, Folder 3)
  - Selma Henke, personal notes on China years, circa 1904-1913 (Box 180, Folder 4)
  - In Memoriam, Lucy A. Gaynor M.D., 1912 (Box 180, Folder 5)
  - Christian Missions in China (Box 180, Folder 6)
  - Christian Missions in China (Box 180, Folder 7)
  - Nanking University, famine relief bulletin, circa 1910 (Flat-box 250, Folder 2)
  - Nanking and Nanking University, maps and surveys, circa 1912 (Flat-box 250, Folder 3)
  - Nanking Incident, 1927 (Box 180, Folder 8)
  - Steve Upton, Nanking Incident, 1927 (Box 180, Folder 9)
  - Steve Upton, Nanking Incident, 1927 (Box 180, Folder 10)
  - Steve Upton, Nanking Incident, 1927 (Box 180, Folder 11)
  - William B. Pettus (Box 180, Folder 12)
  - Minor Searle Bates, letters regarding Nanking, 1930, 1938 (Box 180, Folder 13)
  - John E. Williams of Nanking (W. Reginald Wheeler), 1937 (Box 180, Folder 14)
  - China Coast Family (John C. Caldwell), 1953 (Box 180, Folder 15)
  - Nationalists and the Nanking Incident (Carol E. Doris), 1966 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - To China with Love (Pat Barr), 1973 (Box 181, Folder 2)
  - A Memoir of Revolutionary China, 1924-1941 (Ruth V. Hemenway), 1977 (Box 181, Folder 3)
  - Wuhu General Hospital 1889-1949 (Elsie Hayes Landstrom), 1989 (Box 242, Folder 13)
  - Anna and James McGinnis: Missionaries to China, 1893-1949 (Ann E. McGinnis Baskin), circa 1993 (Box 244, Volume 1)
  - Where I Came from, Where I Went, and so What; or the Life of an American Diplomat (Robert C. Strong), circa 1993 (Box 244, Volume 2)
  - American property losses in China, 1927-1939 (Box 181, Folder 4)
  - Alexander Glover Small, China papers (Box 181, Folder 5)
  - Alexander Glover Small, China papers (Box 181, Folder 6)
  - Alexander Glover Small, Nanking Incident, financial losses, 1927 (Box 181, Folder 7)
  - "Changli War Days of 1925" (Box 181, Folder 8)
  - Alexander Glover Small, maps of Nanking (annotated photocopies), circa 1927 (Map-folder 182)
  - China: the Life and Times of Alexander Glover Small, Mary Miller Small, and Louise Small, 2004 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - How our Bishops Served the Chines e (T. Otto Nall), 1982 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - China American Schools, circa 1988 (Box 183, Folder 3)
  - Travel in China, circa 1980 (Box 183, Folder 4)
  - Travel in China, circa 1980 (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - Travel in China, circa 1980 (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - China subject files, miscellaneous (Box 183, Folder 7)
- Series XV. OVERSIZE
  Oversized materials, such as diplomas and newspapers found throughout the collection and housed separately.
  - Clipping, "China and the Hague", 1908 March 26 (Flat-box 245, Folder 1)
  - Clipping, "China’s Progress" (article about William F. Hummel), 1909 (Flat-box 245, Folder 2)
  - The Chicago Tribune (Paris edition), 1919 June 16 (Flat-box 245, Folder 3)
  - Shanghai Times, 1927 March 29 (Flat-box 245, Folder 4)
  - Clipping, Tsingtao Times (article about Charles Melvin Stuart), 1931 March 31 (Flat-box 245, Folder 5)
  - South China Morning Post, 1934 July 30 (Flat-box 245, Folder 6)
  - The China Press, Silver Jubilee of the Republic of China 1911-1936, 1936 October 10 (Flat-box 246)
  - Clippings, China Press Weekly, circa 1937 (Flat-box 245, Folder 7)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, "Japan Attacks U.S.", 1941 December 8 (Flat-box 245, Folder 8)
  - The Press Democrat, 1960 March 14 (Flat-box 245, Folder 9)
  - Marin Magazine, "The Many Chaptered Life of Stuart Hummel" (photocopy), 1976 June 3 (Flat-box 245, Folder 10)
  - Sonoma Index-Tribune, "Diary of a Lifetime" (article on R. Stuart Hummel), 2005 August 19 (Flat-box 245, Folder 11)
  - Johan Gottlieb (Gottlob) Hummel, commission as Lieutenant in the Union Army, signed by Abraham Lincoln (facsimile copies), 1864 (Flat-box 247, Folder 1)
  - Charles C. Solter and Martha Hummel, diploma and marriage certificate, 1889, 1895 (Flat-box 247, Folder 2)
  - William F. Hummel, diplomas, 1903-1916 (Flat-box 247, Folder 3)
  - Wilhelm Friedrich Hummel (1861-1897) and Caroline Wehking Hummel (1861-1897), tombstone rubbing, Warrenton, Missouri (Flat-box 247, Folder 5)